Contact

jvjvalerio@me.com

www.linkedin.com/in/juliovalerio-779a3181 (LinkedIn) juliovalerio.com (Portfolio) github.com/jvjvalerio (Other)

Top Skills

Computer Hardware Troubleshooting
Remote Troubleshooting
Network Troubleshooting

Languages

Spanish

Certifications

Blockchain Essentials

BTA Certified Blockchain Business Foundations

Architecting with Google Compute Engine Specialization

Google IT Support Professional Certificate

Apple Certified Associate - Mac Integration 10.13

Julio Valerio

Computer Science student at City University of New York-Brooklyn College

Brooklyn

Summary

Curious and motivated engineer with interests ranging from decentralized ledger technologies, product development, software engineering, and IT Support with over 15 years of experience. Currently pursuing a bachelors degree in Computer Science with the goal of building impactful solutions.

Experience

City University of New York-College of Staten Island I.T. Associate Level 1
October 2017 - Present (3 years 11 months)

Staten Island, NY

- -Supervised and provided professional development and establishing work schedules for the technical support unit staff.
- -Provided support to end-users including: identifying, researching and resolving technical problems, and responding to support requests made via telephone calls, e-mails, and the self-service portal.
- -Utilized Bomgar desktop software to support remote control, desktop sharing and file transfer to offsite users.
- -Communicated with technology users and staff to understand, identify, document, and resolve problems.
- -Installed approved software releases, system upgrades, patches, and software related compatibility issues.
- -Maintained, analyzed, troubleshoot, and repaired computer systems, repaired and replaced components in laptops, desktops, printers, and other peripherals.
- -Evaluated, prioritized, and provided support for incoming requests for assistance from end-users experiencing problems with hardware, software, networking, and other IT-related issues.
- -Documented incidents in the KACE ticketing system and ensured timely resolution of open tickets.
- -Maintained classroom SMARTBoard technology to include software updates and general maintenance needs.

- -Managed conference calls and video conferencing software and peripherals. Assisted users with teleconferencing software such as Zoom, Citrix, and Polycom technologies.
- -Created, updated, and managed user permissions and computer and group assignments in Active Directory.
- -Monitored system wide difficulties and worked with the Office of Information Technology team and other support staff in providing timely notification of problem occurrence, updates, and resolution to appropriate groups, as required.
- -Maintained a working knowledge of computer technology, network systems, and standard software and act as a resource of technical information to the end user community.

Google

10 months

Google Software Product Sprint May 2021 - August 2021 (4 months)

New York City Metropolitan Area

- Collaborated with a team of peers to design and implement a web application using Java, Javascript, HTML, and CSS over the course of 10 weeks, leveraging various Google Cloud Platform APIs, including App Engine and Datastore.
- Practiced Industry best practices such as: contributing to open source software using Git and GitHub, conducting code reviews, participating in distributed development, designing new components and interfaces and leading them to completion.

Google's Mentorship and Development Program November 2020 - May 2021 (7 months)

New York, United States

- Participated in Google's CSSI: Online Program a 2-week intensive introductory project-based python processing curriculum taught by Google engineers
- Completed 10 individual coding projects by using concepts such as variables, conditionals, loops

and functions

 Participated in a 1:1 mentorship program with Google Engineers to develop personal and professional goals over a 6 month period LaGuardia Community College IT Support Assistant October 2013 - September 2017 (4 years)

Long Island City, New York

- -Communicated with technology users and other technology staff to understand the details of work assignments and the nature of problems and logged problem reports.
- -Tested computer and communications equipment to check its capacity and capability to perform as specified, and reported findings.
- -Identified problems regarding computer, peripheral, or communications equipment, and other operating environment.
- -Determined the cause of malfunctions and various methods (e.g. observation, use of diagnostic software or equipment).
- -Informed supervisor or designated contact for repairs and followed up to assure problems have been resolved.
- -Performed simple repairs such as replacing faulty computers, peripherals, and communications equipment and/or component parts.
- -Assisted in orientation and training of new staff. Temporarily supervised other personnel.
- -Assisted with data storage operations, Transferred data from one medium/ format to another and performed routine back up and recovery tasks.
- -As directed made minor adjustments and implemented routine technical updates to hardware and software (including networks, operating systems, and applications software.

Best Buy Geek Squad June 2009 - August 2012 (3 years 3 months) 8801 Queens Blvd Rego Park, NY 11373

- Helped drive a positive customer experience by building relationships, exhibiting empathy, and providing solutions for their needs.
- Provided positive, timely engagements with customers during the check-in and check-out process.
- Understood customer's technology issues by asking probing questions, listening, asking clarifying questions, taking detailed notes, and providing accurate time estimates for next steps.
- Monitored queues and providing accurate status updates to customers.
- Clearly communicated and partnered with team members.

Gotham City Mortgage IT Support Specialist May 2004 - June 2009 (5 years 2 months)

Queens, New York, United States

- -Maintained a predictive dialing system for the telemarketing team.
- -Was the sole IT Technician for the office of 30 employees comprised of loan officers, a telemarketing team, and underwriters.
- -Assisted in the setup and installation of VOIP systems.
- -Maintained, analyzed, troubleshot, and repaired computer systems, repaired or replaced components in laptops, desktops, printers, and other peripherals.

Education

City University of New York-Brooklyn College Computer Science · (2021 - 2022)

Laguardia Community College
Associate of Arts and Sciences - AAS, Computer Network Administrations &
Security · (2018 - 2020)

Aviation Career And Technical High School
High School Diploma, Aeronautics/Aviation/Aerospace Science and
Technology, General · (2000 - 2005)